So let's make sure that something useful happens when this button is pressed,
Bu yzden, bu dmeye basldnda yararl bir ey
for that, I will add action creators because of course I want to dispatch an action when this is pressed
olacandan emin olalm, bunun iin, eylem oluturucular ekleyeceim nk elbette bu ilem basldnda
So in my store actions folder,
bir eylem gndermek istiyorum. Bu
I'll add a new file auth.js and there I want to set up authentication related actions,
yzden maaza eylemler klasrnde yeni bir dosya ekleyeceim . js ve orada ben kimlik dorulamas ile ilgili
I now also will set up some action types in the action types file I'll export them and I will add
eylemler kurmak istiyorum, imdi ben de onlar ihra edecek eylem trleri dosyasnda baz
an AUTH_START
eylem trleri
action type, identifier therefore is also AUTH_START and then I'll duplicate it twice
kuracak ve ben bir AUTH_START eylem tr ekleyeceim, tanmlayc ayn zamanda AUTH_START ve sonra ben
to also create an AUTH_SUCCESS
olacak Bir AUTH_SUCCESS eylem tr ve bir
action type and an
AUTH_FAIL ilem tr oluturmak iin iki
AUTH_FAIL action type because obviously, authentication can also fail.
kez oaltn, nk kimlik dorulamas da baarsz olabilir.
Now in
imdi hakszlk iinde. js, tm eylem trlerini eylem trleri olarak ie aktaracam. / actionTypes ve sonra birka
to create a couple of action creators, I'll export them all.
eylemci oluturmak istiyorum, hepsini ihra edeceim.
The first one is the AUTH_START action creator,
Birincisi, AUTH_START eylem yaratcsdr, bunu elbette bir ilev haline
I will make this a function of course,
getireceim, aslnda herhangi bir giri
I don't actually request or require any inputs here,
istemiyorum ya da buna ihtiya duymuyorum, sadece trn
I just want to return a javascript object where the type is of type actionTypes.AUTH_START,
actionTypes trnde olduu javascript nesnesini dndrmek istiyorum. AUTH_START, burada herhangi bir yk aktarmyorum,
I don't pass any payload here,
esasen bu ilemi bir
I will essentially use this action to set a loading state and potentially show a spinner if I want to.
ykleme durumu oluturmak iin kullanacam ve eer istersem potansiyel olarak bir evirici gstereceim.
Next I'll add a const, authSuccess,
Sonra bir const ekleyeceim, authSuccess, bu fonksiyonda
this function here will get some data, auth data
baz veriler, auth verisi alacak ve burada bir javascript nesnesini
and here I want to also return a javascript object, the type will be of type AUTH_SUCCESS, of course
de dndrmek istiyorum, tip AUTH_SUCCESS tipinde olacak ve tabii ki auth
and I'll pass on the auth data,
verisini geeceim Daha sonra
we'll have a look at what this is later. Now we need another action creator here,
ne olduuna bir gz atacaz. imdi baka bir eylem yaratcsna
AUTH_FAIL,
ihtiyacmz var, AUTH_FAIL,
here we get a potential error and I will return a javascript object here too,
burada olas bir hata alyorum ve burada bir javascript
the type will be actionTypes.AUTH_FAIL and I will then pass on the error,
nesnesini de dndreceim, tip actionTypes olacaktr. AUTH_FAIL ve sonra
like so. Finally I'll add one last action type, that will be the one holding the async code doing the
hata iletirim. Son olarak, kimlik dorulamasn yapan bir async
authentication,
kodu tutan
I'll just name it auth, here
tek bir son eylem
I expect to get the email and the password and I will then return dispatch,
tr ekleyeceim, sadece ismini auth ediyorum, burada e-postay ve ifreyi almay bekliyorum
so a function which gets dispatch as an argument
ve sonra gnderimi geri alacam
thanks to redux-thunk and in there, I now want to authenticate the user.
Redux-thunk sayesinde bir argman olarak gnderilebilen ve o anda, kullancnn kimliini dorulamak istiyorum.
Now for now, I'll simply dispatch authStart here to at least set this state,
imdilik, en azndan bu durumu ayarlamak iin authStart' buraya gnderiyorum, imdi de elbette
now with that we of course need to connect our actions to our containers so that we can dispatch them,
ki hareketlerimizi konteynerlerimize balamak zorundayz, bylece onlar gnderebiliriz, bu yzden auth konteynrna
so I'll head over to the auth container and there, I want to import my actions. To do so,
gideceim ve Orada, eylemlerimi almak istiyorum. Bunu yapmak iin, auth eylem
I will add my auth action creators to the index.js
ierik oluturucularm dizine ekleyeceim. Tm ihracatlarm bu
file where I bundle all my exports from that actions folder.
eylemler klasrnden aldm js dosyas.
So I'll export everything I need from ./auth without the file extension
Bylece ihtiyacm olan her eyi ihra edeceim. / uzantl dosya uzants olmadan
and right now, that is really just the
ve u anda, bu
auth method itself.
gerekten sadece auth ynteminin kendisi.
Now with that, we can go back to the auth container and import all the actions here,
imdi bununla birlikte, auth konteynerine geri dnebilir ve burada tm eylemleri ie
so import everything as actions from
aktarabiliriz, bu yzden her eyi eylemler olarak
and now let's go up to the store, to the actions and to the index.js file and now we can add our good
ie aktarn ve imdi maazaya, eylemlere ve endekse gidelim. js dosyas ve imdi bu bileende
old const mapDispatchToProps constant to be able to dispatch something here via props in this component.
sahne araclyla bir ey gndermek iin iyi eski const mapDispatchToProps sabit ekleyebilirsiniz.
So there as always, I will return a javascript object and there I want to create an onAuth prop which
Yani her zaman olduu gibi, bir javascript nesnesi dndreceim ve orada bir eylem olarak benim
I can use as a method which therefore holds a reference to a method where I will eventually dispatch my action
eylemimi gndereceim ve ben eylemi gndermek istiyorum bir ynteme bir referans tutan bir yntem olarak kullanabileceim
and I want to dispatch the auth action.
bir onAuth pervane oluturmak istiyorum .
Now as you saw when we set this up, the auth action requires an email and a password,
imdi bunu ayarladmzda grdmz gibi, auth eylemi bir e-posta
so I do expect to get this here when we execute this property basically, so that I can pass it on when
ve ifre gerektiriyor. Bu nedenle, bu zellii temel olarak altrdmzda, bunu anam
executing auth. mapDispatchToProps does only makes sense if we connect it to this container,
yrtrken iletebilmemiz iin burada beklemeyi bekliyorum. mapDispatchToProps yalnzca bu kapsaycya balanrsak mantkldr,
so I will now import connect from react-redux so that we can do that,
bu yzden imdi bunu yapabilmemiz iin tepki-redux'tan balant
so import connect from react-redux, like this. With that we can go back to the bottom of the file and
alacam, bylece bu ekilde tepki-redux'tan ie aktarm yapalm. Bununla, dosyann sonuna geri dnebiliriz ve imdi mapStateToProps
now execute connect and pass null for mapStateToProps because we don't have that yet and
iin connect ve null komutunu altrabiliriz, nk biz buna ve mapDispatchToProps'a ikinci argman olarak sahip
mapDispatchToProps as the second argument
deiliz ve ayrca tabii
and I'll also wrap my auth container of course.
ki benim auth konteynrm da kaplayacam.
With that, we can execute onAuth on our props in this container and I want to do this whenever the form
Bununla birlikte, bu kapsaycdaki sahnelere onAuth icra edebiliriz ve form gnderildiinde bunu
is submitted.
yapmak istiyorum.
So I will add an onSubmit handler here and execute this submit handler,
Bu yzden bir onSubmit ileyicisini buraya ekleyeceim ve bu ileyici ileyiciyi
I'll add this method to this container,
yrteceim, bu yntemi bu
the submit handler. I do expect to get the event there because I first of all need to call event.prevent
kapsaycya, gnderen ileyiciye ekleyeceim. Olay almay umuyorum nk ncelikle olay armam gerekiyor. ntanml olarak sayfann yeniden
Default to prevent the reloading of the page and thereafter, I want to call this props, onAuth and
yklenmesini engellemek iin nleme ve bu aamalar armak, OnAuth ve yrtmek ve elbette
execute it
e-posta
and of course I need to pass e-mail and password
ve ifreyi gemem gerekiyor,
so I'll reach out to this.state.controls e-mail value and this.state.controls password value.
bylece buna ulaacam. belirtmek, bildirmek. e-posta deerini ve bunu kontrol eder. belirtmek, bildirmek. ifre deerini kontrol eder.
With that, let's save this and let's see if this works.
Bununla, hadi bunu kaydedelim ve bunun ie yarayp yaramadn grelim.
Back in our project I can enter an email address here and a password, if I click submit and inspect
Projemize bir e-posta adresi girebilir ve bir ifre girebilir, eer redux'u tklayp
redux, we see that authStart was dispatched successfully.
tklatrsam, authStart'n baarl bir ekilde gnderildiini grrz.
So that's working but of course nothing else works yet.
Yani bu alyor ama elbette baka hibir ey ie yaramyor.
The next step is to run some async code which actually does authenticate ourselves and as I said, we'll
Bir sonraki adm, aslnda kendimizi kimlik dorulamas yapan baz ezamansz kodlar altrmaktr ve dediim
do this using firebase.
gibi, bunu firebase kullanarak yapacaz.